（雪(ゆき)）あっ
♪〜
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original
Interviews with Monster Girls
The class is astir
I want to let myself go too,
But I end up putting on a fake smile.
Your eyes alone conveyed a competitive spirit
Biting at your lip forcefully.
You once said,
"I wouldn't want to worry what someone thinks
And end up hurting someone else in the process!"
When the chime rings out, as the rain lifts up,
We'll pass the boundaries of our school!
Jumping through the puddles, light will scatter about
Our smiles, and wishes will be so bright!
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original!
〜♪
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
I thought I'd be able to hide that
I'm a snow woman in high school.
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
（雪）
高校では自分が雪女であることを
隠そうと思ってました
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
Entrance
Ceremony
Shibasaki High School
（シャッター音）
If word didn't get around that I was a demi,
（雪）
デミであることを周知されなければ
maybe no one would approach me out of curiosity.
物珍しさで近づいてくる人も
いないだろうと
If I kept my distance,
人と接触しなければ 私の体質で
危害が及ぶこともないだろうと
maybe my nature wouldn't cause
problems for anyone.
But...
ですが…
（佐竹(さたけ)）おっ？
（太田(おおた)）ん？
When I got overheated during PE class,
（雪）
体育の授業中
暑さにやられて体調を崩して
Kusakabe?
You okay, Kusakabe?
Do you feel sick?
someone was about to touch me, so without thinking, I...
体に触れられそうになって
思わず…
I'm a snow woman!
私 雪女だから！
（佐竹）えっ？
Huh?
冷やせば大丈夫だから
I'll be okay once I cool down.
But I ended up fainting and being
carried out on a stretcher.
（雪）
結局 そのあと倒れてしまって
担架で運ばれて…
Stretcher! Someone get a stretcher!
The Little Snow Woman Is Cold
Have you hidden the fact that you're
a snow woman all your life?
（高橋(たかはし)）
お前が雪女であることは
ずっと隠してきたのか？
No, not before I came here.
（雪）いえ これまでは全く
Until I started high school,
高校に上がるまでは
雪の多い田舎町に住んでいたんです
I lived in a rural town, with lots of snow.
Back then, I didn't hide it at all.
そのときは
全然 隠していませんでした
When my temperature got low,
体温が低いのと
I occasionally emanated cold air or
my tears became ice, but that's all.
たまに体から ちょっと冷気や
氷の涙が出るくらいで
No one else was affected,
人に影響を与えるほどではない
些細(ささい)なものだと思ってたんです
and I considered it a minor thing.
So I never had any problems with
my nature as a snow woman.
だから 自分の雪女の体質に
疑問を持ったことは
ありませんでした
つまり こっちに越してから
高校入学までに何かあったと
Then, something happened between
moving here and starting high school?
Exactly.
そういうことです
It was right after I moved here.
引っ越して
すぐのことだったのですが
At the time, I was really depressed.
そのときの私は
すごく気が滅入(めい)っていました
I was so worried about how I'd
fit into a new environment...
新しい環境での生活を思うと
不安でいっぱいで
And I was separated from the friends
I'd known since middle school.
中学校までの友達とは
離れ離れになってしまったし
I'd always lived in the country,
ずっと田舎暮らしだったので
so I wasn't sure if I could make it in the city.
都会でうまくやっていけるか
自信もなくて 怖くて
I was scared.
I wished I could dissolve into the
hot water, like in a fairy tale.
いっそ おとぎ話のように
湯に溶けて
消えてしまえたら楽なのに
As I thought about all that,
そんなことを考えていたとき
ふと違和感を覚えて…
something suddenly felt strange.
湯船に氷が？
Ice formed in your hot bath?
ぞっとしました
It spooked me.
氷は すぐに溶けましたが
The ice melted quickly,
私がお湯を凍らせるほどの冷気を
発したのだとしたら
but if I'd put out enough cold
air to freeze hot water...
The idea was absolutely terrifying.
それは とても恐ろしいことだと
If I directed that cold air at someone, what would happen?
冷気の矛先が人に向かった場合
どうなってしまうのかと
When my high school life began,
I was still stressed about that.
あれこれ悩んでるうちに
高校生活が始まって
人と接触しなければ
大丈夫だろうと
As long as I avoided contact with
everyone, I thought I'd be fine.
And that's why you started
steering clear of others?
（高橋）
それで
避けるようになったってわけか
I'm scared...
怖いんです
I don't know how dangerous I really am.
結局 自分が
どれくらい危険なのか分からない
If I knew that, and could convey it to people,
それが分かって
人に伝えられれば
I could proudly tell everyone
that I'm a snow woman.
胸を張って
私は雪女だと言えるのに
う〜ん 冷気が湯を…
Cold air freezing hot water...
日下部(くさかべ)は ふだん
どうやって風呂に入るんだ？
How do you normally take baths?
えっ？
Eh?
Oh, I mean, what's the water temperature?
（高橋）
ああ いや 風呂の温度とか
家族と 一緒なのかなって
Do you take them with family members?
The same way as everyone else.
（雪）
同じです
40度くらいですかね
About 40 degrees Celsius...
But people say I take relatively short baths.
ただ 私は入浴時間が短いとは
よく言われますけど
And what was that bath like?
それで そのときは？
Was the water any cooler than usual?
いつも以上に
湯が冷めていたりとか…
No, I don't think so.
いえ そんなことはなかったかと
All right...
そうか
氷の涙が出ると言っていたが…
You said your tears also turn to ice?
I wasn't crying or anything.
（雪）別に泣いていたわけでは
それに 氷の粒は
いつの間にか浮かんでいて
The piece of ice just floated
up, all of a sudden.
I see...
（高橋）そうか
What about sweat?
ああ 汗はどうだ？
入浴時にかいた汗が凍ったとか
Maybe the bath made you sweat, and that froze?
Actually, I almost never sweat.
実は私
汗は ほとんどかかないんです
というよりも
かけないというほうが正しいですね
It might be more accurate
to say that I can't sweat.
I can't do it like everyone else.
人より汗をかくのが下手で…
汗腺っていうんですか？
My... sweat glands?
Right, the glands that secrete sweat.
ああ 汗を分泌する器官のことだな
Evidently, I have very few of them.
（雪）
それが すごく少ないそうです
I understand.
なるほど
全く かかないというわけでは
ないのですが
It isn't as if I don't sweat at all, but...
Then, is it possible your sweat froze?
（高橋）
その汗が
凍ったという可能性は？
My sweat hasn't ever frozen before.
汗が凍ったことは
今まで 一度もないんです
あのときだけ凍ったというのは
変かなって
It seems strange it would only freeze this time...
That's true.
そうだな
My tears can freeze anytime, though.
涙は いつだって凍るのに
（チャイム）
あっ
I'm sorry to spend the whole lunch
period talking about this!
すみません
お昼休みをこんな話で
あ… 先生？
Mr. Takahashi?
Huh? Oh, no problem.
えっ？　あっ ああ
Sorry to keep you this long.
呼びつけて悪かったな
教室 戻っていいぞ
You can go back to class.
失礼しました
Excuse me.
Oh, Kusakabe...
（高橋）ああ 日下部
（雪）はい
Yes?
If you're okay with it,
もし よかったらなんだが
また放課後 来てもらえるか？
would you come see me after school?
Sure.
はい
（町(まち)）あっ 日下部さん！
Kusakabe!
Takanashi! Machi!
（雪）小鳥遊(たかなし)さん 町さん
Did you have lunch together?
２人でお昼ご飯？
（ひかり）うん そう
Yep.
Next time, you should join us.
（町）
今度 日下部さんも 一緒に食べよ
Talking with Mr. Takahashi?
（町）
高橋先生の所ってことは
何か相談してたの？
About something specific?
Yeah, but I think I said some weird
things and worried him even more.
（雪）うん
でも 変な話して
余計な心配かけちゃったかなって
Nah, don't worry about that!
（ひかり）ああ それは大丈夫
Mr. Takahashi always wants to talk to demis, right?
先生は いつだってデミちゃんと
語りたいんだから ねっ？
Yeah.
うん
I hope so.
それなら いいんだけど
あっ そうだ
今日 帰り アイス食べ行かない？
Oh, right. Want to get some ice cream after school?
Ice cream?
（雪）アイス？
（ひかり）突然だね
That's kinda out of nowhere.
Recently, I found a great place.
最近 いいお店 見つけたんだ
どうかな？
How about it?
Well...
うん… 考えとくね
I'll think about it.
See you.
じゃあ
The cold air her body generated
（高橋）
体から発せられる冷気で
湯の温度は下げずに氷だけ生成する
snow woman stories
snow woman soft
snow woman
created ice, without lowering
the water temperature.
snow woman
Is that even possible?
そんなことが可能だろうか？
And her tears freeze anytime...
“涙は いつだって”か
Well, for now,
とりあえず
伝承から当たってみるか
I guess I'll check folklore first.
Koizumi Yakumo
Antiques and Ghost Stories
Oddly enough, all the legends about
snow women are kind of sad.
（高橋）
不思議と雪女の伝承は
どれも物悲しい話ばかりだな
I did some more research on snow women.
（高橋）
雪女について改めて調べてみた
まあ 大体の外見は
どの伝承でも同じだな
Their appearance is basically
the same in every legend.
Beautiful women, dressed all in white, with long hair.
白装束で長髪の美しい女性
老婆のパターンもあるな
Some describe elderly women.
All share a basic template.
話にもテンプレートがある
The snow woman approaches a man,
not telling him that she's a snow woman,
雪女は 自分が雪女であることを
隠して男に近づいて
and she asks him for something.
何かを要求するが
断られると悪さをする
If he refuses, she does something mean.
Or if he befriends her, an accident occurs, and she disappears.
あるいは 親しくなるも
何らかのアクシデントで
去ってしまう
Some minor details vary by region,
地域によって細かい違いはあるが
大体どちらかだ
but they're all basically one or the other...
Oh, sorry—
ああ… すまん
Kusakabe!
（高橋）日下部
（雪）はい
Yes?
Do your feet get cold when you're nervous?
お前 緊張すると
足が冷えたりはしないか？
Huh? Yes, actually, they do.
えっ？　ええ 確かに
冷え性なんですかね
I guess I get cold easily.
そうか
I see.
あ…
Eh?
え？
I'm about to tell Kusakabe something
that might really hurt her.
（高橋）
俺は日下部に
とても辛(つら)い 申し訳ないことを
強いようとしている
But I want her to overcome it.
If she can, then...
だが 乗り越えてほしい
そうすれば きっと…
Sorry about that.
（高橋）待たせたな
Yes. I mean, it's okay.
はい　あっ いえ…
There, we go...
（高橋）う〜し　しょっと
Is that hot water?
（雪）それは お湯？
Yeah, a foot bath.
（高橋）うん 足湯　じゃあ…
Now...
（雪）へ？
Eh?
How's the temperature?
（高橋）湯加減はどうだ？
It's all right.
大丈夫です
Now, then...
（高橋）
でだ
これを朗読してもらえるか？
Would you read this aloud for me?
I compiled some legends about snow women.
雪女の伝承をまとめたものだ
Is this necessary?
必要なことなんでしょうか？
It's important.
大事なことだ
As much as it pains me, I want you
to read it and memorize it.
非常に心苦しいが 頭に残しながら
しっかり読んでほしい
分かりました
Okay.
"One night, amidst a raging blizzard,
a beautiful woman,
“ある吹雪の激しい夜”
“男の所に白ずくめに長い髪の
美しい女が訪ねてきた”
with long hair and white clothes,
came to a certain man's home.
Her body was as cold as ice.
“女の体は
氷のように冷たかったため”
So he tried to get her to bathe,
“男は女を風呂に入れようとするが
女は かたくなにそれを拒んだ”
but she vehemently refused.
He forced her into the bath,
“無理に風呂に入れると
女の体は溶けて消えてしまい”
and she dissolved into the water.
Only a shard of ice remained."
“あとには
つららのかけらだけが残っていた”
Keep going.
（高橋）続けて
All right.
はい
“ある村にきこりを生業(なりわい)としている
２人の男がいた”
"Two woodcutters lived in a certain village.
One winter night,
“ある冬の日 小屋で
２人が寒さをしのいでいると”
they were inside, sheltering from the cold,
when a woman clad in white,
with cold eyes, appeared...
“白装束に身を包んだ
冷たい目をした女がやって来た”
The woman breathed her white
breath upon the older man,
“女は老いたほうの男に
白い息を吹きかけた”
and he was instantly encased in ice.
“すると男は
たちまち氷漬けになって…”
The younger man was so shocked,
he could do nothing but watch.
“目の前で起こったことに”
“若い男は ただ見ていることしか
できなかった”
The woman hovered over the younger man,
“女は若い男に覆いかぶさるが”
but she only smiled at him
and didn't take his life..."
“笑みを浮かべただけで
男の命を… 取らず…”
もういい くさか…
あっ 日下部！
That's enough, Kusaka—
Kusakabe!
はい！
Yes?
Look at the water.
（高橋）湯を見ろ
あっ！　こっ 氷…
I-Ice?
Yeah.
（高橋）うん 間違いなく氷だな
This is definitely ice.
I was right.
（高橋）やはり
（雪）やはり？
You were?
See? This ice is your sweat.
ああ この氷は汗だ
Sweat? But I don't really...
汗？　でも 私は汗は…
This is the sweat produced
due to emotional stress.
（高橋）
これは精神的負荷によってかいた
いわゆる冷や汗だ
What they call a "cold sweat."
A cold sweat?
冷や汗
Remember when I asked if your feet
get cold when you're nervous?
（高橋）
さっき 緊張すると
足が冷えたりしないか尋ねたろう？
ええ
Yes.
Cold sweat usually breaks out on
your forehead, palms, and soles.
冷や汗は額 手のひら
足の裏といった場所によくかく
あっ
Oh!
That's right. You sweat from
the soles of your feet.
そうだ
お前は足の裏に冷や汗をかくんだ
That's amazing.
すごいです
なぜ分かったんですか？
How did you figure that out?
Based on the legends.
（高橋）根拠は伝承だ
Most snow woman legends are sad stories
雪女の伝承は 実らぬ恋 孤立無援
溶けて露と消えてしまう…
about unfulfilled love, isolation,
and melting away into dew.
悲しい話が多すぎる
So I thought
だから 思ったんだ
that negative feelings and emotional stress
ネガティブな感情
精神的負荷自体が
must play a major role in
a snow woman's nature.
雪女の性質に
大きく関わっていると
Then, sweat due to stress would
probably freeze, as well.
ならば ストレスで発生する汗も
凍るんじゃないかと
Sorry to put all that strain on you.
いろいろと
お前に負担をかけて悪かった
えっ
Huh?
In order to prove my theory, I had to
make you as nervous as possible.
（高橋）これを実証するには
できるだけ
お前に緊張してほしくてな
I'm sorry.
すまなかった
N-Not at all!
あっ い… いえ！
I know you did it to assuage my concerns!
私の悩みを
解決するためのことですし
This does assuage them, right?
解決でいいんですよね？
It sure does.
ああ そうだ
湯船の氷は お前の冷や汗だった
The ice in the bath was your cold sweat.
考え事によって
気持ちが こわばったことが原因だ
It happened because you were thinking
about things that made you tense.
Meaning, you don't need to worry
about the cold air you generate.
加えて体から発せられる冷気も
気にすることはない
It's barely enough to cool hot water at all.
湯がほとんど冷めない程度の
影響力だからだ
A snow woman's peculiarities are minor.
雪女の性質は些細なもの
The way you felt about your nature
in middle school wasn't wrong.
中学までのお前の考えは
間違ってはいなかった
There's nothing to worry or stress
yourself about, Kusakabe.
悩む必要も 気に病むこともない
日下部
You aren't the kind of demi
that would hurt anyone.
お前は人を傷つけるような
そういうデミじゃないよ
Don't worry.
安心しろ
（雪）うっ… よかった
Thank goodness.
I'm so relieved!
本当に よかった
If a snow woman's unique traits occur
as a result of negative emotion,
（高橋）
雪女の性質が ネガティブな感情に
起因して起こるのなら
then they won't occur if
she's happy and relaxed.
うれしさや安堵(あんど)といった感情では
発現しない
Warm tears don't freeze.
温かい涙は凍らない
From now on, I hope you'll be able
to shed lots of those tears.
これからは そんな涙が
たくさん流せるといいな
What words would you use to describe
my nature as a snow woman?
（雪）
私のこの性質 言葉にすると
どういう感じなんでしょうか？
Hmm...
う〜ん
"The crystallization of bodily fluids
released under stress," perhaps?
ストレス下における
排出された体液の結晶化
といったところかな
You're literally a "crystallization
of sweat and tears"!
まさに汗と涙の結晶だな
う…
Um, I'm sorry I didn't know
how to react to that.
（雪）えっと…
うまく リアクションできなくて
すみません
No, it's fine... I'm sorry...
（高橋）いや いいんだ　すまん
あの…
その氷の汗 どうするんですか？
Um, what are you going to
do with that frozen sweat?
え？
Huh?
Since I have it, I thought I'd analyze
its components at my college—
せっかくだから 大学で
成分分析してみようかと
Analyze its components?!
成分分析？　やめてください！
それは さすがにセクハラです
Please don't!
That's no less than sexual harassment!
Huh? I can't?
（高橋）ええ？　ダメか？
Absolutely not!
絶対ダメです！
But what's the problem?
別にいいじゃないか
冷たいヤツだな
You're so cold...
That's because I'm a snow woman!
私 雪女ですから
（ひかり）
う〜ん
ユッキー いないみたい
I don't see Yukki in there.
Maybe she already went home...
（町）先に帰っちゃったのかな？
Takanashi! Machi!
（雪）小鳥遊さん！　町さん！
（ひかり）ユッキー？
Yukki?
ああ… よかった　まだ いた
I'm so glad you're still here!
Why are you in such a rush?
どうしたの？
そんなに慌てて
Oh, well...
（雪）うん　あのね…
Let's go get ice cream!
アイス 食べ行こ！
Interviews with Monster Girls
Here's your mango ice cream.
（店員）マンゴーでございます
Thank you!
（女子）ありがとうございます
Come again.
（店員）また来てね
（女子）は〜い
I will!
（ひかり）わっ
（雪）ア… アイス おいしいね
Th-The ice cream's really good, huh?
I-It sure is!
そっ そうだね
（町）うん
Yeah.
（ひかり）う…
When I first met Yukki, I clung to her a lot...
（ひかり）
ユッキーと出会ったばかりは
よく くっついたりしてた
But she didn't seem to like it,
でも そういうの
好きじゃない感じだから
so I put a little distance between us.
少し距離を置いちゃって
And then, that happened.
あんなこともあったし
Yes, Yukki is a demi, but it doesn't matter!
確かにユッキーはデミだけど！
マッチー 大丈夫？
食べにくくない？
You okay, Macchi? Is it hard for you to eat?
It's in a cup, so I'm fine.
カップの
アイスにしたから
Thanks.
ありがとね
小鳥遊さん
Takanashi!
Yes?
（ひかり）はいっ
（雪）よ…
W-Would you like... a taste of mine?
よかったら
私の食べてみる？
Huh? Are you sure?
（ひかり）えっ いいの？
G-Go ahead.
ど… どうぞ
Y-Yay—
わっ わ〜… いっ！
（ひかり）わはっ
（雪）ん？
あ…
I-I'd love some...
も… もらいま〜す
（雪）あっ は〜い
Sure.
The mint is so refreshing and tasty!
I'm happy Yukki invited me,
（ひかり）
ユッキーのほうから誘われたのは
うれしいけど
I-Isn't it?
but I wonder how she feels about me.
ユッキーは
私のこと どう思ってるのかな？
Uh...
（ひかり）あ…
S-S-Sorry, Yukki! I ate too much!
ごご… ごめん ユッキー
食べ過ぎちゃった！
No, it's okay.
いいよ 大丈夫
Takanashi...
小鳥遊さん
うん？
Um, there's something I want to apologize to you for.
（雪）その…
私 小鳥遊さんに
謝りたいことがあって
（ひかり）えっ？
Huh?
You realized that I avoided contact
with others, didn't you?
小鳥遊さん
私が人と触れ合うのを避けてたこと
気付いてたでしょ？
うっ
So you stopped clinging to me,
like you did when we first met,
だから 出会ったころみたいな
抱きつきも やめてくれて
and started to keep a distance.
距離を取ってくれて
I was really happy that
you were so considerate.
小鳥遊さんの心遣いは
本当にうれしかった
でも それで小鳥遊さんが
嫌な思いをしていたのなら
But if you felt bad because of it...
あ…
本当にごめんなさい
I'm really sorry.
（ひかり）
そんな
嫌な思いなんてしてないし…
No, I didn't feel bad at al—
But it's okay now.
（雪）でも もう大丈夫だから
あっ？
Huh?
When it comes to interacting with people, well...
なんていうか
人と触れ合うことについて その…
I've reached a compromise with myself, I guess.
自分の中で折り合いがついたの
So,
だからね
これからは
どんどん触ってきてくれていいから
from now on, you can touch me all you like.
くっついてきてくれて
大丈夫だから
You can even cling to me.
うう〜　ユッキー！
Yukki!
Sheesh, that didn't take long.
もう また急に
（ひかり）エヘへ
I'm so glad.
よかった
I thought I'd made you hate me.
私 ユッキーに
嫌われちゃったのかなってさ
Of course not.
そんなことないよ
But I was so happy when you
invited me to come here...
でもね
ユッキーに誘ってもらえたのが
やっぱり すごくうれしくて
それで…
So...
あ？
Sorry, Yukki, but can I bite you a little?
（ひかり）
ごめん ユッキー
ちょっと噛(か)んでいい？
えっ？
Huh?
Y-You'll suck my blood—
ち… 血を吸うの？
N-No! No!
（ひかり）
違う 違う
たまに歯が痒(かゆ)くなるっていうか
It's just, my teeth sort of itch sometimes,
and I want to chew on someone...
うずうずして
カジカジしたくなっちゃった
Chew on?
カジカジ？
Just a tiny bit, through your clothes!
（ひかり）服の上から軽くだから
All right, sure.
うん いいよ
（ひかり）本当？
Really?!
Okay, here I come—
（ひかり）じゃあ 失礼しま〜…
（雪）ひゃっ
Nom, nom, nom, nom...
（ひかり）カジカジ カジカジ…
（雪）ちょっと くすぐったい
Hey, that tickles...
（雪）
ちょっと ちょ… 小鳥遊さん
ちょ… ちょっと タイム
Wait, T-Takanashi...
W-Wait, time-out!
町さん？
Machi?
I've, also,
（町）
私も ずっと日下部さんと
仲良くなりたいと思ってて
wanted to be friends with you
for a long time, Kusakabe.
So I'm really happy.
だから うれしい
Machi...
町さん
Anyway, once again.
じゃあ 改めて
Nom, nom, nom, nom...
カジカジ カジカジ…
Come on, you're doing this again?
（雪）ちょっと まだやるの？
Your hands feel so nice and cool!
（町）
日下部さんの手
冷たくて気持ちいい
（雪）え〜？　町さんまで
You, too, Machi?
Back when there was still
segregation and opposition,
（高橋）
デミの伝承は
まだ差別や対立構造のあった時代
legends about demis were born of
emotions such as awe and fear.
デミに対する
畏怖とも取れる感情を礎にして
形を成した
That's why there aren't many happy,
light-hearted legends about them.
故にデミの伝承に
明るく愉快な話は少ない
Snow women, with their particular traits,
雪女も その性質と相まって
悲劇的な結末を迎える話が多かった
often met tragic endings in their stories.
But I don't believe snow women today
ただ 現代を生きる雪女が
伝承と同じ道を歩むかとなると
are fated to walk the path of
their counterparts in legend.
それはないだろう
（ひかりたちの笑い声）
Because at the very least...
（高橋）
なぜなら 少なくとも…
（笑い声）
Jeez, that's crazy!
（雪）もう めちゃくちゃだよ〜
...this snow woman is friends with
a vampire and a dullahan.
（高橋）
雪女は
バンパイアやデュラハンと仲良し
There are no legends about a
group like that anywhere.
そんな伝承は
どこにも存在しないからだ
When you want to bite people,
what do you normally do?
ふだん噛みつきたいときは
どうしてるの？
ひまりにお願いしてる
I ask Himari.
ひまり〜
カジカジ カジカジ
Himari... Nom, nom, nom, nom.
（ひまり）んっ
Nom, nom, nom, nom...
（ひかり）カジカジ カジカジ…
次のページ
Turn the page.
（ひかり）
ん〜 カジカジ カジカジ…
Nom, nom, nom, nom...
Wow, Himari must be really nice.
（雪）
へ〜
ひまりちゃん 優しいんだね
Thank you for lunch.
エヘへ
Hey.
（高橋）よう
（３人）ん？
一緒に昼メシか？
Eating lunch together?
'Sup teach?
（ひかり）先生
Hello.
（２人）こんにちは
Glad to see you're all such good friends.
（高橋）
みんな 仲良しこよしで何よりだ
Yes, Hikari and Kyouko have been wonderful to me.
本当に ひかりと京子(きょうこ)には
よくしてもらってます
Hikari? Kyouko?
ひかり？　京子？
Th-There's nothing wrong with me
calling them by name, is there?
いっ いいじゃないですか
別に名前で呼んだって
It's great that you're so close,
仲がいいのは結構だが
あまりハメを外し過ぎんようにな
but just try not to get carried away.
Kusakabe and Machi should be fine.
日下部と町は
大丈夫そうだが…
But, Hikari, you'd better be a little careful.
ひかり
お前は ちょっと注意だな
Huh, what do you mean? No fair!
え〜 何それ？　心外
Why do you only use Hikari's given name?
どうして
ひかりだけ名前呼びなんですか？
Oh, because Takanashi Himari.
ああ ひまりちゃんがいるから
うん うん
Yep, yep.
ひまりちゃんは
ちゃん付けなんですが…
You used her fullname, though.
ゴホン
Uh... Good morning, Takanashi.
えっと… おはよう 小鳥遊
G-Good morning, Mr. Takahashi.
あ… おはようございます 先生
ぎこちない
So awkward.
Takanashi Hikari!
ひかりちゃ〜ん
Yep!
は〜い
That reaction seems annoying to do.
リアクション めんどくさそう
ひかり？
Hikari...
What's up?
なになに？
O-Okay, I kind of get the idea.
（雪）
な… なんとなく分かりました
Then, couldn't you use Kyouko's given name, too?
じゃあ 別に
京子のことも名前で呼んであげても
いいんじゃないでしょうか？
へ？
（高橋）
ん？　まあ 別に俺はかまわんが
Well, I wouldn't mind that...
Kyouko...
京子
Kyouko. Kyouko.
（高橋）
京子 京子…
（町）
あっ やっぱり町で大丈夫です
Actually, you can just call me "Machi."
（高橋）あ… そうか？
Really?
Ha! She shot you down!
（ひかり）
や〜い フラれてやんの〜！
（高橋）なに？　こら ひかり！
（ひかり）や〜い や〜い！
Huh? Hey! Hikari!
Nyah!
いいの？
Are you sure?
Hold it!
Yeah, it's a little embarrassing...
うん　ちょっと恥ずかしいし
No way!
Besides, my family name, Machi,
sounds like a given name,
それに町って名字も
響きが名前みたいで
so I'm happy to be called that.
呼ばれてて うれしいの
（高橋）そもそもだ
For starters...
（２人）ん？
If you're going to talk about others
with given names, start with her.
名前の呼び方で審議すべきは
まず こいつだろ
Aw, he caught me...
"Yukki" and "Macchi" are one thing.
“ユッキー”“マッチー”
大いに結構
But, well, Hikari...
（高橋）だがな ひかり
（ひかり）ん？
What about Mr. Katou, the Japanese teacher?
（高橋）
現国の加藤(かとう)先生は？
Mr. Katou.
（ひかり）
加藤先生
And Ms. Yachigusa, the school nurse?
（高橋）
保健の八千草(やちぐさ)先生は？
Ms. Yachigusa.
（ひかり）
八千草先生
See? You address all the others properly,
な？　ほかの先生は
ちゃんと名前で呼ばれてるのに
so why am I the only one different?
なぜ俺は“先生”なんだ？
Can't you just call me "Mr. Takahashi" every time?
普通に“高橋先生”じゃ
いけないのか？
Huh? But you just seem like a "Teach" sometimes.
え〜？　だって
先生は“先生”って感じだから
What does that even mean?
（高橋）何だ そりゃ？
I get it.
（町）分かる
（雪）それは分かる
I totally get it.
By the way, what do you call Ms. Satou?
あっ そういえば お前
佐藤先生は何て呼んでるんだ？
Sakki.
サッキー
Sakki? Is she your friend now?
（高橋）サッキー？　友達なの？
（２人の笑い声）
Was Kusakabe always that cheerful?
（佐竹）
日下部って
あんなに明るかったっけ？
No idea.
（太田）さあ
Oh, Hikari. Fifth period is P.E.
（町）
あっ ひかりちゃん
５時間目 体育だよ
Oh, that's right! We have to change!
そうだった！
着替えないと
See you, Yuki.
雪ちゃん またね
Yeah.
（雪）うん
（ひかり）バ〜イ
Bye!
Come on!
She's so boisterous.
まったく 騒々しいな
She sure is.
そうですね
Well, I'll get going, too.
（高橋）じゃ 俺も行くな
（雪）あっ
ん？　どうかしたか？
Something wrong?
No, I mean, um...
いや その… えっと…
何でもないです
It's nothing.
No?
そうか？
じゃあ またな　雪
Then, see you later,
Yuki.
あっ
Er, I thought maybe you wanted
me to call you that...
いや…
そう呼んでほしかったのかな〜って
Um, well,
えっと その…
I guess it doesn't matter what you call me.
名前の呼び方なんて
どうでもよくないですかね？
H-Huh?
ええ〜
Man, I wasn't even thinking.
（ひかり）いや〜 うっかりしてた
After Mr. Takahashi barged in, I completely forgot.
先生の乱入でコロッと忘れてた
Same here.
（町）そうだね
なあ 小鳥遊
Hey, Takanashi...
（ひかり）
んっ 何？
急いでるんだけど
What's up? We're kinda in a hurry.
Give me a nickname, too.
俺にもあだ名 付けてくれよ
えっ？
え〜と ちょっと それは…
Uh, I'm not really sure I can...
いいじゃねえか 大丈夫だ
どんなのだっていいからさ
Come on, it's cool.
Anything is fine, so just give me one!
遠慮せず言ってくれ
Sorry. What was your name again?
ごめん　名前 何だっけ？
You're in different classes. It happens.
（太田）
クラスも違うんだし
しかたないよ
Satake...
（雪）佐竹君
（佐竹）ん？
Hmm?
Um, when I collapsed before,
thanks for asking if I was okay.
その… 前に倒れたとき
すぐに声かけてきてくれて
ありがとう
Sorry it took me so long to say.
お礼を言うのが遅れて
ごめんなさい
Also, sorry for being mean after you were
kind enough to invite me to hang out.
あと
せっかく遊びに誘ってくれたのに
邪けんにしてしまって
それでね 放課後 遊びに行かない？
カラオケとかどうかな？
So, would you like to hang
out today, after school?
Maybe we could go for karaoke?
Sure... Sounds good.
うん いいね
よかった　じゃあ
Great! See you later!
Yes!
しゃ〜！
ハハハッ ハハハハハ！
Oh? You're the only boy?
（雪）
あれ？　男子は佐竹君 １人？
Satake, is something wrong?
佐竹君 どうかした？
♪〜
The events of a mysterious world,
Like the ones you hear of in fairy tales,
Are actually closer than you think
Just like the way you and I met!
When I stood up tall to gaze at
The familiar scenery outside my window,
Even days that felt like torture seemed precious somehow.
Stuck in my heart, I can't put them into words
How should I try to put these feelings into words?
Laughing over stupid things...
Getting mad over small details...
We'll keep carving these trivial moments into our hearts.
Sometimes I'm feeling sad...
But when I'm with you, I'm so happy!
We'll keep on building these irreplaceable moments,
And little by little, we'll come to understand one another.
〜♪
Next Time
The Takanashi Sisters Don't Fight
Next time on Interviews with Monster Girls:
（ひまり）
次回 「亜人ちゃんは
語りたい」
The Takanashi Sisters Don't Fight.
「小鳥遊姉妹は
争えない」